Register of the Seymour Weiss papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Seymour Weiss papers
1943-1998
99004
Hoover Institution Archives
27 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (11.6 linear feet)
The papers of Seymour Weiss document his long career as an analyst at the U.S. Department of State. Working closely with his counterparts in the Department of Defense, Weiss specialized in the fields of nuclear strategy and arms control. The bulk of his papers consist of correspondence, memoranda, photographs, and reports, among which are numerous studies of the strength of the Soviet military and analyses of treaties such as the Strategic Arms Limitation Treaties (SALT I and II).
Weiss, Seymour.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1999.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1925 May 15 Born, Chicago, Illinois
1968-1969 Director, Office of Strategic Research and Intelligence, U.S. Department of State
1972-1973 Deputy Director, Policy Planning Staff, U.S. Department of State
1973-1974 Assistant Secretary of State for Politico-Military Affairs, U.S. Department of State
1974-1976 U.S. Ambassador to the Bahamas
1992 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of Seymour Weiss document his long career as an analyst at the U.S. Department of State. Working closely with his counterparts in the Department of Defense, Weiss specialized in the fields of nuclear strategy and arms control. The bulk of his papers consist of correspondence, memoranda, and reports, among which are numerous studies of the strength of the Soviet military and analyses of treaties such as the Strategic Arms Limitation Treaties (SALT I and II).
Weiss was skeptical about Soviet intentions and any agreements to limit or reduce the nuclear arsenal of the United States. In the late 1970s, Weiss was part of the Team B undertaking, in which a group of outside experts looked at the question of the size and nature of Soviet nuclear forces. Team B produced a classified report that diverged from those prepared by the U.S. government. Materials related to Team B can be found in the Subject File. Weiss also served as an advisor to the Reagan presidential transition team, and materials related to this can be found in the Subject File.
The papers also include the many opinion pieces that Weiss wrote after leaving government service. These were published in newspapers like The Wall Street Journal, The Washington Post, and The New York Times and focused largely on various arms control initiatives and the process of détente with the Soviet Union. Weiss remained hawkish in his views and was critical of any accommodation of the Soviet Union on the part of the United States.
United States--Defenses.; United States--Military policy.; Security, International.; Nuclear weapons.; Arms control.; United States--Foreign relations--1969-1974.; United States. Department of State.
- Biographical File, 1943-1994 (Box 1)
  - College transcript, 1946-1994 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Military records, 1943-1994 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Obituary, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Personnel file, 1949-1994 (Box-folder 1: 4-5)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes correspondence between Richard N. Smith and United States Office of Personnel Management.
- Correspondence, 1976-1992 (Boxes 1-2)
  - Barker, Robert B., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Brennan, Donald G., 1979 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Cooper, Henry F., Jr., 1983 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Defense Nuclear Agency, 1982-1992 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Denech, F. R., Jr., 1985 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Doyle, William L., Jr., 1981 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Dunne, Gerald W., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Ermarth, Fritz W., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Foster, John S., 1985 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Gaffney, Henry H., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Griff, Len, 1976 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Hagemann, Kenneth L., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Ikle, Fred, 1985 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - International Republican Institute (Jack Buechner), 1992 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Jenkins, Frank, 1992 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Joint Chiefs of Staff, Joint Strategic Target Planning Staff, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Kelso, Frank B., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Kenyon College (Frank Baumann), 1984 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Larson, C. R., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Lehrman Institute (Nicholas X. Rizopoulos), 1981 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Marshall, Andrew, 1985 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Martin, J. J., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Martus, M. F., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - May, Ernest R. and James E. Goodby, 1987 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Merrill, John, 1986 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - National Academy of Public Administration (Donald E. Smith), 1987 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Neumann, Ronald E., 1980 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - Prociv, Theodore M., 1983 (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - Rostow, Gene, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 36)
  - Rumsfeld, Donald, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - Saxer, Richard K., 1987 (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - Sloss, Leon, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - Stark, J. R., 1992 (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - Wagner, Rich, Jr., 1991-1992 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Watkins, James D., 1983 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Weinberger, Caspar, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Wohlstetter, Albert, 1983 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Speeches and Writings, 1973-1992 (Boxes 2-5)
  - Speech, U.S. Air Force Scientific Advisory Board, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - "Secretary Kissinger's Defense of Detente,", 1975 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - "U.S. National Security Imperatives,", 1976 November 10 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - With Paul H. Nitze and John F. Lehrman, The Carter Disarmament Proposals: Some Basic Questions and Cautions, 1977 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - "The Role of Allied Nuclear Forces,", 1977 July 12 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - "Some Thoughts on a Comprehensive Test Ban,", 1977 July 19 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Article on Soviet military policy, 1977 August 5 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Draft statement on SALT for Senator Baker, 1977 November 3 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - "Follow Up to the Kupperman Study on Terrorism,", 1977 November 23 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - With Eric Fromm, President Carter's Arms Transfer Policy: A Critical Assessment, 1978 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - "Mr. Kennan Should Clarify Views on Soviet Policy," Wall Street Journal, 1978 January 27 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Transcript of interview, MacNeil/Lehrer Report, 1978 April 10 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Transcript of remarks, The Advocates, 1978 April 13 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - "National Intelligence and the USSR," National Review, 1978 June 23 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - "Dealing with the Problem of Gaining a Widespread Public Appreciation of the Implications of a Strategic Balance,", 1979 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - "U.S./European Relationship in the 1980s,", 1979 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - "Factors Which Bear upon the Potential of Allies to Contribute to an Improved Western Strategic Posture for the Early 80s,", 1979 March (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - "The Political Context of SALT II,", 1979 May 15 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - "'War Monger' Fear Isn't a Reason to Buy SALT," Wall Street Journal, 1979 May 24 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - "Implications of Revised U.S. SALT Position,", 1979 Summer (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - Questions on SALT, 1979 Summer (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - Notes for speech on multilateral force, 1979 June (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - "A Question Which Requires Serious Attention,", 1979 June (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - "As It Stands Now, There Is No Safety in SALT," Los Angeles Times, 1979 August 26 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Letter to the editor, Washington Post, 1979 September 3 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - "Soviet Troops in Cuba: Ominous Portent,", 1979 September 7 (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - Notes on SALT treaties and arms control, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 2: 31)
  - Notes on NATO, 1980 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - With Leon Sloss, "U.S./European Relationship in the 1980s," (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - "U.S. Surrogate Program,", 1980 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Writings on terrorism, 1980 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - "Soviets on Military Strength,", 1980 January (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - With Fred S. Hoffman and Leon Sloss, "Alliances under Stress,", 1980 April (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - "The Politico-Military Context of CW Treaty Verification and Compliance,", 1981 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - "SALT,", 1981 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - "SALT: A Bad Agreement Better Than No Agreement?,", 1981 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Unpublished article on American security assistance, 1981 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - "The NSC Is No Place for Active Military Officers," Wall Street Journal, 1981 February 4 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - "Random Thoughts on U.S. Policy toward East-West Relations,", 1981 March 2 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - "Arms Transfer Programs under the Reagan Administration,", 1981 April 30 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - "AWACS Bears Bitter Fruit," Wall Street Journal, 1981 May 1 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - "Tne Human Rights Office Was a Poor Idea", 1981 June 9 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - "'Strategic Stability'-Paths and Prospects," New York Times, 1981 July 26 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - "Secretary Haig's New Framework for Arms Control," Wall Street Journal, 1981 July 27 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - With William R. Van Cleave, "A Conceptual Framework for SALT,", 1981 August (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Editorial submitted to Wall Street Journal, 1981 August 15 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - "The Risks of Cutting the Defense Budget," Wall Street Journal, 1981 September 11 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - "Support for Reagan's Arms Speech Will Fade," Wall Street Journal, 1981 November 30 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - "The Reagan Response on Poland," Wall Street Journal, 1981 December 29 (Box-folder 3: 22)
  - Article on NATO and no first use of nuclear weapons, 1982 (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - "Organization for Nuclear Crises Management,", 1982 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - "Political Realities and Military Planning in NATO,", 1982 (Box-folder 3: 25)
  - Writing on arms control, 1982 (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - Writing on nuclear winter, 1982 (Box-folder 3: 27)
  - Writing on START talks, 1982 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - "President Must Hang Tough, Ignore Advice to Compromise His Plan," Conservative Digest, 1982 January (Box-folder 3: 29)
  - "The Role of Congress in Nuclear War,", 1982 February (Box-folder 3: 30)
  - "U.S. National Interests and Protracted Nuclear War,", 1982 March 4 (Box-folder 3: 31)
  - "The Foreign Policy Debate Disintegrates," Wall Street Journal, 1982 March 23 (Box-folder 3: 32)
  - "The Current Debate over Nuclear Arms," Wall Street Journal, 1982 April 20 (Box-folder 3: 33)
  - Review of book by Henry Kissinger, 1982 May 13 (Box-folder 3: 34)
  - "Arms Control Verification and Survivability of TNF", 1982 May 27 (Box-folder 3: 35)
  - Unpublished article on Alexander Haig's resignation, 1982 June 25 (Box-folder 3: 36)
  - "Why We Must Think about Protracted Nuclear War," Wall Street Journal, 1982 August 30 (Box-folder 3: 37)
  - Writing on nuclear strategy, 1982 November 9 (Box-folder 3: 38)
  - Transcript of panel discussion, Heritage Foundation, 1983 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Unpublished article on arms control, 1983 January (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - "...But Let's Not Overlook the Hurdles," Wall Street Journal, 1983 April 8 (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - "The Anti-Nuclear Weapons Movement," speech, U.S. Conference of Catholic Bishops, 1983 May 3 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Unpublished article on START, 1983 June (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Unfinished article on Central American policy of U.S. government, 1983 August (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Unpublished article on arms control, 1983 August (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - "What If the Soviets Mean Every Deed of It?," Wall Street Journal, 1983 September 23 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Unpublished article on arms control, 1983 October (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Questions about Ballistic Missile Defense, 1983 November 1 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Unpublished article on arms control, 1984 February 16 (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - Unpublished letter to the editor, Washington Post, 1984 May 18 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - "Contemporary U.S./USSR Arms Control Negotiations: Bane or Salvation?,", 1984 April 17 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - "Mr. Nixon's Chimerical Detente," Wall Street Journal, 1984 June 4 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - "The Case against Arms Control," Commentary, 1984 November (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Unpublished article on arms control, 1984 November 14 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - "Strategic Defense", 1984 December 12 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - "Theater Nuclear Force Initiatives,", 1984 December 21 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Article on summit conference, 1985 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - "Contingency Planning Involving the Potential Use of U.S. Military Force,", 1985 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Notes on the Soviet Union, 1985 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Unpublished article on U.S./USSR summit meetings, 1985 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - "Contemporary U.S./USSR Arms Control Negotiations,", 1985 January (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - With Leon Sloss, "Raging against 'Star Wars,'" Washington Post, 1985 January 7 (Box-folder 4: 24)
  - Unpublished article on arms control, 1985 January 15 (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - "Is a Workable Arms-Control Pact Possible?," interview, U.S. News & World Report, 1985 January 21 (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - "Hard Questions about Arms Control," Reader's Digest, 1985 March (Box-folder 4: 27)
  - Interview, Policy Review, 1985 March-April (Box-folder 4: 28)
  - Salt II: Rest in Peace, roundtable discussion, 1985 March 28 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - Unpublished article on liberalism, 1985 April (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - "Strategic Defense - A Third View,", 1985 April 2 (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - "Summits: Substance as Important as Tactics,", 1985 April 30 (Box-folder 4: 32)
  - Transcript of remarks, Face the Nation, 1985 June 9 (Box-folder 4: 33)
  - "Get Prepared for the Next Crisis," Wall Street Journal, 1985 July 2 (Box-folder 4: 34)
  - "SDI and Offensive Warhead Reductions,", 1985 August 14 (Box-folder 4: 35)
  - Unpublished article on U.S./USSR summit, 1985 September (Box-folder 4: 36)
  - Speech at christening of USS Indomitable, 1985 November (Box-folder 4: 37)
  - Unpublished article about SDI, 1986 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Unpublished article on SALT II for Wall Street Journal, 1986 April (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Unpublished article on SALT II, 1986 April (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - "Memorandum on the Prospective Initial Use of Nuclear Weapons by the U.S.,", 1986 May 20 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - "SDI, Arms Controls, and U.S. Foreign Policy" in SDI in the Near Term: Strategy, Technology and the ABM Treaty, 1986 July 15 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - "Sounding a Retreat on SDI," Wall Street Journal, 1986 July 30 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - "Approaching Summit II: A Case for Wariness," Christian Science Monitor, 1986 August 25 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Unpublished article on SDI, 1986 Winter (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - "Misrepresenting Rowny," Evening Sun, 1986 November 26 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - "U.S. National Security Interests and Objectives Today,", 1987 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Writing on INF Treaty, 1987 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - "Arms Control: Just Say No," Wall Street Journal, 1987 May 13 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Unpublished article on ABM Treaty, 1987 August 4 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - "Shultz's Troubling Testimony," Wall Street Journal, 1987 August 6 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Unpublished article on arms control, 1987 September (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Unpublished article on INF Treaty, 1987 October (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Article against INF Treaty, 1987 November (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - "INF Pact Limits Our Conventional 'Smarts' as Well," Wall Street Journal, 1987 November 16 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Unpublished article on INF Treaty, 1987 December (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - "Detente and My Relationship with Kissinger,", 1988 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - "Detente and Technology,", 1988 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - "Reform in the Soviet Union - Déjà Vu?,", 1988 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - "NATO after INF,", 1988 February 6 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Writing on INF Treaty, 1988 April 10 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Unpublished article on INF Treaty, 1988 April 20 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - "Labyrinth Under Moscow," Washington Post, 1988 May 25 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - With Richard Pipes, "The Record of 'Team B,'" Washington Post, 1988 August 21 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Writing on detente, 1988 December-1989 January (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - "Detente: The Emperor Has No Clothes,", 1989 (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Unpublished writing on Gorbachev, 1989 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - "A European Arms Pact?," New York Times, 1989 March 11 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - Unpublished writing on INF Treaty, 1989 May (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - Unpublished article on arms control, 1989 September (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Unpublished article on U.S./Soviet relations, 1989 October 23 (Box-folder 5: 34)
  - "U.S.-Soviet Detente: The Collision of Hope and Experience," Strategic Review, 1989 Winter (Box-folder 5: 35)
  - Speech on arms control, 1990 (Box-folder 5: 36)
  - Unpublished article on nuclear strategy, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 37)
  - Unpublished article on use of nuclear weapons in Gulf War I, 1991 January 7 (Box-folder 5: 38)
  - Writing on U.S. nuclear policy, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 39)
  - "Anti-Ballistic Missile Defense,", 1992 (Box-folder 5: 40)
  - "Getting Intelligence Estimates Right: The 'Team B' Experience,", 1992 (Box-folder 5: 41)
  - "Intelligence in National Security Affairs,", 1992 (Box-folder 5: 42)
  - Unpublished article on Gulf War I, 1992 (Box-folder 5: 43)
  - "The Role of Nuclear Weapons after the Cold War,", 1992 February 11 (Box-folder 5: 44)
  - "Will No One Defend Defense?," Wall Street Journal, 1992 February 18 (Box-folder 5: 45)
  - Unpublished article on chemical weapons, 1992 April 21 (Box-folder 5: 46)
- Office File, 1953-1997 (Boxes 6-20)
  Comprised of correspondence, memoranda, and reports relating to Seymour Weiss's career in the U.S. State Department.
  - Freedom of Information Act requests, 1992 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Records of transferred and destroyed files, 1959-1967 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - File register prepared by Richard Smith, 1997 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - 1953-1954 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - 1955 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - 1956 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - 1957 (Box-folder 6: 7-8)
  - 1958 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - 1959 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - 1960
    - January-June (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - July-December (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - 1961
    - January-April (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - May-June (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - July-August (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - September (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - October (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - November-December (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - 1962
    - January (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - February (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - March-April (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - May (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - June-July (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - August-November (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - December (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - 1963
    - January (Box-folder 8: 8)
    - February (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - March (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - April (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - May (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - June (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - July-August (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - September, 1963 (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - October (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - November (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - December (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - 1964
    - January (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - February (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - March (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - April (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - May (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - June (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - July-August (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - September (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - October (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - November (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - December (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - 1965
    - January (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - February (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - March (Box-folder 11: 10)
    - April (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - May-June (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - July-August (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - September (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - October-December (Box-folder 12: 5)
  - 1966
    - January (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - February (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - March (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - April (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - May (Box-folder 12: 10)
    - June (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - July-August (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - September-October (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - November-December (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - 1967
    - January (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - February-April (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - May (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - July-September (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - 1968
    - January (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - July-August (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - September-October (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - November-December (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - 1969
    - January-February (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - March (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - April (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - May (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - June (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - July (Box-folder 14: 10)
    - August-September (Box-folder 14: 11)
    - October (Box-folder 14: 12)
    - November-December (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - 1970
    - January (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - February (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - March (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - April (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - May (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - June-July (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - August-September (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - October (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - November (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - December (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - 1971
    - January (Box-folder 15: 11)
    - February (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - March (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - April (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - May-June (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - July-August (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - September (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - October (Box-folder 16: 7)
    - November (Box-folder 16: 8)
    - December (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - 1972
    - January (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - February (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - March (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - April (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - May (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - June (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - July (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - August (Box-folder 17: 8)
    - October-November (Box-folder 17: 9)
    - December (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - 1973
    - January-February (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - March (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - April (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - May (Box-folder 18: 5)
    - June (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - July-August (Box-folder 18: 7)
    - September (Box-folder 18: 8)
    - October (Box-folder 18: 9-10)
    - October (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - November (Box-folder 19: 2-4)
    - December (Box-folder 19: 5-6)
  - 1974
    - January-February (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - March (Box-folder 19: 8)
    - April (Box-folder 19: 9)
    - May (Box-folder 20: 1)
    - June-August (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - September (Box-folder 20: 3)
    - October-November, 1974 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - 1975
    - January-February (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - March-April (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - May-September (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - October-December (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - 1976
    - January-March (Box-folder 20: 9)
    - May-June (Box-folder 20: 10)
    - July-November (Box-folder 20: 11)
- Richard N. Smith File, 1992-1998 (Box 21)
  Consists of correspondence relating to Smith's efforts to obtain documents under the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act.
  - 1992-1995 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - 1996 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - 1997-1998 (Box-folder 21: 3)
- Writings by Others, 1952-1992 (Box 21)
  - Ball, George W., 1982-1983 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Bennett, William J., 1992 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Fromm, Erik M., 1987 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Gray, Colin S., 1981 (Box-folder 21: 7)